Curriculum Vitae

Liam McLeod

Home Telephone: (01424) 433655, Email: <u>L McLeod95@hotmail.com</u> / <u>LiamMcLeod@bexhillcollege.ac.uk</u> http://dual1ty.me/

491 Bexhill Road, St Leonards-on-Sea, East Sussex, TN38 8AT

Key Skills:

- IT literate -Excellent knowledge of Microsoft Office and other specialist software suites, applications and programming: Including Adobe Photoshop, Visual Studio, Eclipse, NetBeans, Blender; Web Development in HTML, CSS (& SASS), PHP and JS (& Node) in their most recent iterations using a variety of tools, and finally application development, specifically in VB.NET, Java and JS.
- Polite, well spoken and literate.
- Base knowledge in a wide range of subjects:
 - Computer systems and servers,
 - Networking,
 - Web development (HTML, CSS, JS),
 - Database design, MySQL, SQL
 Server and PostgreSQL,

- NodeJS and PHP,
- Designing and manipulating computer graphics,
- System and network security,
- Scientific writing.

Personal Skills:

- Good communication

- Flexible

- Problem Solving

- Numeracy, Literacy and IT Skills
- Independent (but adaptable)
- Dedicated

Education and Training

2015-Current

University of Brighton, Priory Street, Hastings, TN34 1EA, United Kingdom

- 2015-18: Computer Systems with Networking (Hons) BSc

2011-2015:

Bexhill 6th Form College, Penland Road, Bexhill-on-Sea, TN40 2JG, United Kingdom

2011-12: Guitar Enrichment2013-14: Volunteer Enrichment2011-13 Level 3 Specialist National2013-15: AS Computing (B), A-Level

Diploma in IT (DMM), Psychology (D)

2006-2011:

The Grove, Darwell Close, St Leonards-on-Sea, East Sussex, TN38 9JP

- GCSEs: Maths (C), English (C), Catering (C), English Literature (B), Sciences: Chemistry: (B), Physics: (B), Biology: (B) and Geography (C).
- BTECs: Level 2 Information Technology (Distinction) and Physical Education (Merit).

Employment and Experience

2010:

The Grove, Darwell Close, St Leonards-on-Sea, East Sussex, TN38 9JP

Teaching Assistant for Music, English and Sciences (Work Experience)

Curriculum Vitae

2013-Current:

Bexhill 6th Form College, Penland Road, Bexhill-on-Sea, TN40 2JG, United Kingdom

- Volunteer Enrichment (2013-14)
- Volunteer in IT Faculty (2015-16) Reporting to Gary Newport

2015-Current:

Freelance Web Developer

- PMJ Groundworks (defunct)
- Examplar (Exam Paper Search Tool)
- Project X (Work in progress)

Personal Statement:

Availability: I can be available to start work as soon as required and I am able to work extra hours so long as this does not conflict with current commitments at university. Therefore, I would find employment preferable if provided with flexibility to fit around my current studies at the University of Brighton.

Leisure Interests: My leisure and recreational interests include web development, music, politics and sciences. For the most part this includes making web applications for learning new technologies, playing guitar. It is for this reason I decided to take my education further and study areas of computer science further at Brighton University, I volunteer in the IT Faculty of Bexhill College. To back this further I have previously had work experience at the Grove College as a Teaching Assistant where I assisted in the preparation, teaching and covering of lessons spanning English, the sciences, religious education and music. I enjoy a range of other activities predominantly learning, reading and live musical performances (attending and playing). This is why I decided to make the most of my opportunities at Bexhill College where I have studied four subjects and voluntarily assisted in the maintenance of the IT department resources resulting in me being invited back to assist in the teaching, generation of resources and running of student support sessions. Due to this, I have consistently maintained a hunger and drive to learn new things especially within the fields of IT and the sciences, all of which I consider instrumental to success and important aspects to life and my development.

Personal Statement: I am a polite, well-mannered person who is keen to learn new skills and adapt to new environments. I am sociable, hardworking and determined with my work. My ideal employment would be to work within an IT based environment. However, I am happy to adapt to any environment required. I am aspirational and keen to work my way up within a business. Throughout my entire academic career I have strived to maintain a high-level of quality in my work, punctuality and my attendance, which has consistently been 100% up until my final year in college, something I know can only be an asset to any employer.

References

(Academic / Employer References)

Gary Newport

Teacher, IT Course Manager and Employer at Bexhill College (2013-16)

garynewport@bexhillcollege.ac.uk

Bexhill College Penland Road

Bexhill-on-Sea

East Sussex

TN40 2JG

(Personal Reference)

Holly Wright

Partner

holly.wright@outlook.com 4 Catsfield Close St Leonards-on-Sea East Sussex TN38 9TA